Guide to the Jascha Heifetz Collection ARS.0046
Archive of Recorded Sound
- 12" Sound Discs, 78 rpm discs
  - Commercially Released Recordings, 78 and 33 rpm discs
    - Box 9: His Master's Voice/RCA Victor/Gramophone, 78 rpm discs
      - Glazunov, Aleksandr Konstantinovich, 1865-1936. Concertos, violin, orchestra, op. 82, A minor -- Glazunov, Aleksandr Konstantinovich, 1865-1936. Méditation, 3 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 9, Disc 317-319)
        Performed by Jascha Heifetz, violin; London Philharmonic Orchestra; John Barbirolli, conductor
        His Master's Voice: D.B.2196; 2B6853-2[square], 2B6854-1[square] (matrix); 32-4474, 32-4475 (additional matrix nos.) -- D.B. 2197; 2B6855-1[square], 2B6856-1[square] (matrix); 32-4476, 32-4477 (additional matrix nos.) -- D.B. 2198; 2B6857-1[square], 2B6103-2[square] (matrix); 32-4478, 32-4480 (additional matrix nos.)
      - Cavalcade of famous artistes: 1910-1935, 2 12" shellac 78 rpm sound discs (Box 9, Disc 320-321)
        Repertoire unspecified on disc.
        Performers: Paderewski, McCormack, Casals, Melba, Kreisler [Side 1]; Rachmaninoff, Tetrazzini, Pachmann, Caruso [Side 2]; Menuhin, Galli-Curci, Chaliapine, Cortot, Gigli [Side 3]; Backhaus, Schumann, Horowitz, Melchior, Elgar [Side 4]
        Jubilee Record 1910-1935 (Gramophone): D.B.2454; 2EA.271-8[square], 2EA.272-7[square](matrix)-- D.B. 2455; 2EA277-4[square], 2EA278-5[square]
      - Tchaikovsky, Peter Ilich, 1840-1893. Concertos, violin, orchestra, op. 35, D major, 4 12" shellac 78 rpm sound discs (Box 9, Disc 322-323)
        His Master's VOice: D.B.3159; 2EA4709-1A[square], 2EA4710-2[square] (matrix) -- D.B.3160; 2EA4711-2A[square], 2EA4712-1A[square] (matrix) -- D.B.3161; 2EA4713-1A[square], 2EA4714-1[square] (matrix) -- D.B.3162; 2EA4715-1A[square], 2EA4716-1[square] (matrix)
      - Franck, César, 1822-1890. Sonatas, violin, piano, A major, 3 12" shellac 78 rpm sound discs (Box 9, Disc 326-328)
        Performed by Arthur [sic] Rubinstein, piano; Jascha Heifetz, violin
        His Master's Voice: D.B.3206; 2EA4883-1[square], 2EA4884-1[square] (matrix) -- D.B.3207; 2EA4885-1[square], 2EA4886-1[square] (matrix) -- D.B.3208; 2EA4887-1[square], 2EA4888-1[square] (matrix)
      - Bazzini, Antonio, 1818-1897. Ronde des lutins -- Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Stimmungsbilder. An einsamer Quelle, 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 9, Disc 329)
        Performed by Jascha Heifetz, violin; Emanuel Bay, piano [side A]; Arpad Sandor, piano [side B]
        His Master's Voice: D.B.3214; 2EA4895-1[square], 2B6042-3[square]
      - Wieniawski, Henri, 1835-1880. Polonaise brillante, no. 1; arr. -- Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. Impromptus, piano, D. 899. No. 3; arr., 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 9, Disc 330)
        His Master's VOice: D.B.3215; 2EA4856-2[square], 2A78974[diamond]
      - Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Ägyptische Helena. Selections, 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 9, Disc 331)
        Titles on labels: Act 1, Helen's awakening [side A], Act 2, Funeral march [side B]
        Performed by Grand Symphony Orchestra; Fritz Busch, conductor
        Odeon: 5163; XXB8185-2, XXB8187
      - Lehár, Franz, 1870-1948. Friederike. Sah ein Knab' ein Röslein stehn -- Lehár, Franz, 1870-1948. Friederike. O Mädchen, mein Mädchen, 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 9, Disc 332)
        Performed by Richard Tauber, tenor; unidentified orchestra
        Odeon: 85201; XXB 8110-3; XXB 8111-3 (matrix)
      - Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. Quartets, strings, D. 804, A minor, 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 9, Disc 333)
        Disc is badly cracked and has been moved to Box 1.
        Performer unspecified
        Telefunken: EH 5823; 021621, 021622 (matrix)
    - Box 16: Victor, 78 rpm discs
      Choruses, Secular (Men's voices) with orchestra; Songs (High voice) with orchestra; Songs (High voice) with piano; Operas -- Excerpts, Arranged; Schipa, Tito; Philadelphia Orchestra; Ruffo, Titta; Gluck, Alma; Elman, Mischa; Clément, Edmond; Echániz, José; Stokowski, Leopold, 1882-1977; Gigli, Beniamino; Werrenrath, Reinald; Morini, Erica
      - Massenet, Jules, 1842-1912. Manon. En fermant les yeux je vois -- Lalo, Edouard, 1823-1892. Roi d'Ys. Aubade, 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 16, Disc 638)
        Titles on labels: Le rêve (The dream) Act 2 [side A] – Le roi d’Ys-Vainement, ma bien aimée (The king of Ye-In vain, my beloved) [side B]
        Performed by Edmond Clement; Frank La Forge, piano
        Victrola: F 6062A-1, K 6062B-2 (matrix)
      - Massenet, Jules, 1842-1912. Thaïs. Méditation -- Rimsky-Korsakov, Nikolay, 1844-1908. Zolotoĭ petushok. Otvetʹ mne, 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 16, Disc 639)
        Title on Side B label: Hymn to the sun (from Le coq d’or-The golden cockerel)
        Performed by Mischa Elman, violin; Josef Bonime, piano
        Victrola: W 6100A-3-2, F 6100B-1-1 (matrix)
      - Bland, James A. (James Allen), 1854-1911. Carry me back to old Virginny -- Foster Stephen Collins, 1826-1864. Old Black Joe, 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 16, Disc 640)
        Additional title on Side A: Plantation melody
        Performed by Alma Gluck, soprano; unidentified male chorus and orchestra
        Victrola: 4P 6141A-1-1, 4C 6141B-6-9 (matrix)
      - Chopin, Frédéric, 1810-1849. Waltzes, piano, op. 18, E♭ major -- Kreisler, Fritz, 1875-1962. Alt-Wiener Tanzweisen. Liebesleid; arr., 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 16, Disc 650)
        Additional title on Side B: Love’s sorrow (Old Vienna waltz)
        Victrola: H 6259A-1-2, B 6259B-5-1 (matrix)
      - Leoncavallo, Ruggiero, 1858-1919. Pagliacci. Prologo, 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 16, Disc 651)
        Additional title information on labels: Si può! – A word; Un nido di memorie – A song of tender memories
        Performed by Titta Ruffo, baritone; unidentified orchestra
        Victrola: E 6268A-1-2, F 6268B-1 (matrix)
      - Pérez Freire, Osmán, 1880-1930. Ay, ay, ay -- Palacios, Cristóbal. A Granada., 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 16, Disc 653)
        Additional titles on label: Canción andaluza; To Granada
        Performed by Tito Schipa, tenor; unidentified orchestra
        Victrola: V 6423A, L 6423B-1-1 (matrix)
      - Sarasate, Pablo de, 1844-1908. Carmen fantaisie -- Zarzycki, Aleksander, 1834-1895. Mazurkas, violin, orchestra, op. 26, G major; arr., 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 16, Disc 654)
        Title and performer information handwritten in pencil on label.
        Performed by Erika Morini, violin; Emanuel Balaban, piano
        Victrola: J 6445A-3-7, A 6445B (matrix)
      - Flotow, Friedrich von, 1812-1883. Martha. Ach! so fromm, ach! so traut –- Drigo, Riccardo, 1846-1930. Millions d'Arlequin. Sérénade, 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 16, Disc 655)
        Additional titles on labels: Like a dream [side A]; Love's nocturne (Notturno d'amor) [side B]
        Performed by Beniamino Gigli, tenor; unidentified orchestra
        Victrola: J 6446A-1-4, O 6446B-4-4 (matrix)
      - Ippolitov-Ivanov, Mikhail Mikhaĭlovich, 1859-1935. Kavkazskie ėskizy. V aule -- Borodin, Aleksandr Porfirʹevich, 1833-1887. Kni︠a︡zʹ Igorʹ. Polovet︠s︡kai︠a︡ pli︠a︡ska. Selections., 1925 April 29; 1925 May 15; 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 16, Disc 657)
        Additional titles on labels: In the village (Dans l'aoule): no. 2 of Caucasian sketches [side A]; Prince Igor-Polovetzki dance [side B]
        Victrola: 2 0 6514A-2-2, 2 M 6514B-2-3 (matrix)
        Recorded May 15, 1925 [side A]; April 29, 1925 [side B]
      - Liszt, Franz, 1811-1886. Liebesträume, voice, piano. O lieb, so lang du lieben kannst. Italian -- Schipa, Tito, 1889-1965. Ave Maria., 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 16, Disc 658)
        Additional titles on labels: Dream of love [side A]; Ave Maria (Hail, Mary) [side B]
        Performed by Tito Schipa, tenor; Echániz, José, piano [side A]; unidentified orchestra [side B]
        Victrola: C 6543A-13, B 6543B-5-1 (matrix)
      - Strauss, Johann, 1825-1899. An der schönen, blauen Donau -- Strauss, Johann, 1825-1899. G'schichten aus dem Wienerwald, 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 16, Disc 659)
        Additional titles on labels: Blue Danube waltz (Danubio azul-vals) [side A]; Tales from the Vienna Woods waltz (Cuentos del Bosque de Viena vals) [side B]
        Victrola: 8U 6584A-6-6, 9C 6584B-3 (matrix)
      - Debussy, Claude, 1862-1918. Plus que lente; arr. – Debussy, Claude, 1862-1918. Preludes, piano, book 1. Fille aux cheveux de lin – Grieg, Edvard, 1843-1907. Stemninger. Scherzo-impromptu, 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 16, Disc 662)
        Additional titles on labels: Waltz [side A]; The maiden with flaxen hair [side B]
        Victrola: O 6622A-6, N 6622B-3 (matrix)
      - Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Rienzi. Ouvertüre – Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Ring des Nibelungen. Götterdämmerung. Brünnhildes Schlussgesang. Grane, mein Ross!, 1926 November 18; 1927 January 6; 2 12" shellac 78 rpm sound discs (Box 16, Disc 663-664)
        Additional title information on side B: Götterdämmerung-Closing scene (Twilight of the Gods)
        Victrola: Y 6624A-1, R2 6624B-2 (matrix); C2 6625A-2, L 6625B-2 (matrix)
        Recorded November 18, 1926, and January 6, 1927.
      - Damrosch, Walter, 1862-1950. Danny Deever – Speaks, Oley, 1874-1948. On the road to Mandalay, 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 16, Disc 665)
        Performed by Reinald Werrenrath, baritone; unidentified orchestra
        Victrola: 2M 6638A-11-2, E 6638B-5-1 (matrix)
      - Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. Ellens Gesang, D. 839; arr. -- Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. Sonatas, piano, D. 850, D major. Rondo; arr., 1946 September 27; 2 12" shellac 78 rpm sound discs (Box 16, Disc 668a-668b)
        Title on Side A of each disc: Ave Maria
        Victrola: 3D 6691A, K 6691B (matrix nos.) [Disc 668a]; D3 6691A, O 6691B (matrix nos.) [Disc 668b]
      - Achron, Joseph, 1886-1943. Hebrew melody; arr. -- Sarasate, Pablo de, 1844-1908. Danzas españolas, op. 23. Zapateado, 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 16, Disc 671)
        Additional title information on side B label: The cobbler (Spanish dance), op. 23, no. 6
        Performed by Jascha Heifetz, violin; Isidor Achron, piano.
        Victor: 2F 6695A, S 6695B (matrix)
      - Debussy, Claude, 1862-1918. Prélude à l'après-midi d'un faune., 1927 March 10; 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 16, Disc 672)
        Title on label: Afternoon of a faun
        Performed by the Philadelphia Symphony Orchestra; Leopold Stokowski, conductor
        Victrola: I2 6696A, 2L 6696B (matrix)
      - Mussorgsky, Modest Petrovich, 1839-1881. Boris Godunov (Rimsky-Korsakov). Proshchaĭ, moĭ syn! umirai︠u︡, 2 12" shellac 78 rpm sound discs (Box 16, Disc 673a-673b)
        Titles on labels: Farewell of Boris (Farewell, my son, I am dying) (Act 4) [side A] -- Death of Boris (Hark! 'tis the passing bell) (Act 4) [side B]
        Performed by Feodor Chaliapin, bass; unidentified orchestra
        Victor: C 6724A, 2 6724B; CR375-1[triangle], Cc10938-3[triangle] (matrix nos.) [copy a] -- 6724A, 6724B; CR375-1[triangle], Cc10938-3[triangle] (matrix nos.) [copy b]
      - Stravinsky, Igor, 1882-1971. Zhar-ptit︠s︡a., 1927 October 12; 3 12" shellac 78 rpm sound discs (Box 16, Disc 674-676)
        Titles on labels: The firebird (L'oiseau de feu)
        Victrola: B 6773A, A 6773B (matrix) [Disc 674]; A 6774A, B 6774B (matrix) [Disc 675]; A 6775A, A 6775B (matrix) [Disc 676]
      - Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix, 1809-1847. Gesänge, op. 34. Auf Flügeln des Gesanges; arr. -- Falla, Manuel de, 1876-1946. Canciones populares españolas. Jota; Grieg, Edvard, 1843-1907. Lyriske stykker, op. 71. Småtrold., 1946 September 27; 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 16, Disc 679)
        Titles on labels: On wings of a song (Auf Flügeln des Gesanges) [side A] -- Jota; Puck [side B]
        Victor: K 6848A, B 6848B (matrix)
      - Strauss, Johann, 1825-1899. Wiener Blut (Waltz) -- Strauss, Johann, 1825-1899. Frühlingsstimmen., 1928 December 18; 1928 December 20; 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 16, Disc 680)
        Additional titles on labels: Wiener Blut-Walzer (Vienna blood-waltz) [side A] -- Voices of spring-Waltz [side B]
        Victrola: O 6903A, K 6903B (matrix)
        Recorded December 20, 1928 [side A], and December 18, 1928 [side B]
      - Tchaikovsky, Peter Ilich, 1840-1893. Capriccio italien., 2 12" shellac 78 rpm sound discs (Box 16, Disc 681-682)
        Additional title on labels: Italian caprice, op. 45
        Victor: B 6949A-1, C 6949B-2 (matrix); B2 6950A-3, C6950B-2 (matrix)
    - Box 17: Victor/RCA Victor/Victrola, 78 rpm discs
      New York Philharmonic; Toscanini, Arturo; Mengelberg, Willem, 1871-1951; Boston Symphony Orchestra; Victor Symphony Orchestra; Moiseiwitsch, Benno; Philadelphia Orchestra; Stokowski, Leopold, 1882-1977; Koussevitzky, Serge; Amans, John; Tibbett, Lawrence; Flagstad, Kirsten; Pelletier, Wilfrid; Lange, Hans; Thibaud, Jacques; Coates, Albert; Cortot, Alfred; London Symphony Orchestra; Shilkret, Nathaniel; Continental Symphony Orchestra; Caruso, Enrico; Coppola, Piero; Balsam, Artur; Menuhin, Yehudi, 1916-1999; Casals, Pablo
      - Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Traviata. Atto 1o. Preludio -- Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Traviata. Atto 3o. Preludio, 1929 March 18; 1929 March 29; 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 17, Disc 683)
        Title on label: Traviata: Prelude to Act 1 -- Traviata: Prelude to Act 3
        Performed by the Philharmonic-Symphony Orchestra of New York; Arturo Toscanini, conductor
        Victrola: L 6994A-3, F 6994B-3 (matrix)
        Recorded March 18 and 29, 1929
      - Rimsky-Korsakov, Nikolay, 1844-1908. Svetlyĭ prazdnik, 1929 January 26; 2 12" shellac 78 rpm sound discs (Box 17, Disc 684-685)
        Title on label: Overture: Parts 1-4 (“Grande Pâque Russe”) (Russian Festival of High Easter) Op. 36
        Victor: 7018 A-1, 7018 B-3A (matrix, disc 684); 7019A-2A, 7019B-1 (matrix, disc 685)
      - Dukas, Paul, 1865-1935. Apprenti sorcier, 1929 March 18; 2 12" shellac 78 rpm sound discs (Box 17, Disc 686a-686b)
        Title on labels: L’apprenti sorcier: Parts 1-2 (The Sorcerer’s Apprentice) (After a ballad by Goethe)
        Victor: x7021A-3, 12-7021B-2 (matrix, disc 686a); Victrola: L 7021A-3-2, P 7021B-2 (matrix, disc 686b)
      - Haydn, Joseph, 1732-1809. Symphonies, H. I, 101, D major. Vivace -- Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix, 1809-1847. Sommernachtstraum. Scherzo, 1929 March 29; 1929 March 30; 2 12" shellac 78 rpm sound discs (Box 17, Disc 687a-687b)
        Titles on labels: Symphony No. 4, in D Major (“The Clock”) Part 7-4th Movement-Finale-Vivace -- Midsummer Night’s Dream-Scherzo (After Act 1)
        Victor: 7080-A, 7080B [both discs]; 48945-3, 48948-3 (matrix) [disc 687a]; w 48945-3, w 48948-3-1 (matrix) [disc 687b]
      - Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Symphonies, K. 385, D major. Presto -- Gluck, Christoph Willibald, Ritter von, 1714-1787. Orphée et Eurydice. Ballet des ombres heureuses, 1930?; 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 17, Disc 688)
        Titles on labels: Symphony in D Major (K. No. 385) 4th Movement-Finale-Presto -- Orfeo ed Euridice-Dance of the spirits (Act 2)
        Performed by the Philharmonic-Symphony Orchestra of New York; Arturo Toscanini, conductor; John Amans, flute solo [side B]
        Victor: 7138A, 7138B; 48952-3-2, 48956-6c-3 (matrix)
      - Ravel, Maurice, 1875-1937. Daphnis et Chloé. Suite, no. 2, 1928 December 20; 2 12" shellac 78 rpm sound discs (Box 17, Disc 689-690)
        Victor: 7143A-2, 7143B-5 (matrix); D 7144A-5, S 7144B-3 (matrix)
      - Albéniz, Isaac, 1860-1909. Iberia. Fête-Dieu à Séville, 1928 September 27; 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 17, Disc 691)
        Title on label: Holiday in Seville
        Victrola: B 7158A-2A, B 7158B-1A-1
      - Prokofiev, Sergey, 1891-1953. Symphonies, no. 1, op. 25, D major -- Prokofiev, Sergey, 1891-1953. Li︠u︡bovʹ k trem apelʹsinam. Suite. Skert︠s︡o -- Prokofiev, Sergey, 1891-1953. Li︠u︡bovʹ k trem apelʹsinam. Suite. Marsh, 1929 April 22; 2 12" shellac 78 rpm sound discs (Box 17, Disc 692-693)
        Title on labels: Classical Symphony, in D Major (Prokofieff) [disc 692, both sides, and disc 693, side A] -- Love for three oranges-Scherzo and march (Prokofieff) [disc 693, side B]
        Victrola: H 7196A-1R, J 7196B-4-1 (matrix); F 7197A-4, H 7197B-1 (matrix)
      - Rossini, Gioacchino, 1792-1868. Barbiere di Siviglia. Sinfonia, 1929 November 21; 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 17, Disc 694)
        Title on label: Barber of Seville-Overture-Parts 1 and 2
        Victrola: o 7255A-2-2, 1 7255B-3 (matrix)
      - Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Salome. Salomes Tanz -- Eichheim, Henry, 1870-1942. Oriental impressions. [title from label:] Japanese nocturne, 1929 April 30; 1929 May 1; 2 12" shellac 78 rpm sound discs (Box 17, Disc 695-696)
        Title on labels: Salome’s dance-Parts 1-3
        Victrola: A 7259A-2, B 7259B-2 (matrix); D 7260A-2, B 7260B-3 (matrix)
        Recorded May 1, 1929 [Strauss], and April 30, 1929 [Eichheim]
      - Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827. Egmont. Ouverture, 1930 January 14; 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 17, Disc 697)
        Title on label: Egmont overture-Parts 1 and 2 (Beethoven, Op. 84)
        Performed by the Philharmonic-Symphony Orchestra of New York; Willem Mengelberg, conductor
        Victor: B2 7291A-1, Y 7291B-1 (matrix)
      - Sibelius, Jean, 1865-1957. Finlandia, 1930 April 28; 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 17, Disc 698)
        Title on label: Finlandia-Parts 1 and 2 (Tone poem) (Sibelius, Op. 26, no. 7)
        NB: Recording of complete tone poem, op. 26; not only op. 26, no. 7.
        Victor: H 7412A-1, 4[backwards]E 7412B-2A (matrix)
      - Ravel, Maurice, 1875-1937. Valse -- Debussy, Claude, 1862-1918. Dances, piano; arr., 1930 October 30; 2 12" shellac 78 rpm sound discs (Box 17, Disc 699-700)
        Title on label: Danse (Claude Debussy) (Orchestrated by Ravel)
        Victrola: B 7413A-3, A 7413B-2 (matrix); B 7414A-2, A 7414B-2 (matrix)
      - Tchaikovsky, Peter Ilich, 1840-1893. 1812 année, 1930 April 29; 2 12" shellac 78 rpm sound discs (Box 17, Disc 701-702)
        Title on labels: 1812 Overture-Parts 1-4 (Tschaikowsky, Op. 49)
        Victor: 7499A-2A, 7499B-2A (matrix); B 7500A 3-23A, B 2 7500B-3A (matrix)
      - Bach, Johann Christoph, 1642-1703. Aus der Tiefe rufe ich; arr., 1930 March 15; 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 17, Disc 703)
        Title on label: Choral prelude-“Aus der Tiefe rufe ich” (Out of the deep I call to Thee) ([J.S.] Bach)
        NB: Attributed to both J. C. Bach and C.P.E. Bach.
        Victrola: B[?] 7553A-3A, C 7553B-3 (matrix)
      - Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856. Kinderscenen, 1930 April 14; 2 12" shellac 78 rpm sound discs (Box 17, Disc 704-705)
        Title on labels: Scenes of childhood [Nos. 1-13]
        Performed by Benno Moiséivitch, piano
        Victor: D 7705A-2-1, D 7705B-8-1; Cc 16233 5[triangle], Cc 16234 8[triangle] (additional matrix nos., disc 704); J 7706A-5-1, C 7706B-2-1; Cc 16235-5[triangle], Cc 16236-6[triangle] (additional matrix nos., disc 705)
      - Leoncavallo, Ruggiero, 1858-1919. Pagliacci. Vesti la giubba -- Flotow, Friedrich von, 1812-1883. Martha. Ach! so fromm, ach! so traut. Italian, 1932 August 15; 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 17, Disc 706)
        Title on label: Marta-M’apparì [side B]
        Performed by Enrico Caruso, tenor; Victor Symphony Orchestra; Nathaniel Shilkret, conductor
        RCA Victor: J 7720A-1, I 7720B-1 (matrix)
        Originally recorded March 17, 1907 [side A] and April 15, 1917 [side B] with Josef Pasternack conducting; re-recording from original dubbed with electrically recorded orchestra August 15, 1932, with Nathaniel Shilkret conducting
      - Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Aïda. Celeste Aïda -- Bizet, Georges, 1838-1875. Pêcheurs de perles. Je crois entendre encore, 1932 December 3; 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 17, Disc 707)
        RCA Victor: B 7770A-1, A 7770B-1 (matrix)
        Originally recorded December 27, 1911 [side A] and December 7, 1916 [side B] with Josef Pasternack conducting; re-recording from original dubbed with electrically recorded orchestra December 3, 1932, with Nathaniel Shilkret conducting
      - Ravel, Maurice, 1875-1937. Tzigane, 1932 May 23; 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 17, Disc 708)
        Performed by Yehudi Menuhin, violin; Arthur [Artur] Balsam, piano
        Victrola: A 7810A-2, A 7810B-2-1; 2L316-2[triangle], 2L319-2[triangle] (additional matrix nos.)
      - Gruenberg, Louis, 1884-1964. Emperor Jones. Standin' in de need of prayer -- Hanson, Howard, 1896-1981. Merry Mount. 'Tis an Earth defiled, 1934; 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 17, Disc 713)
        Performed by Lawrence Tibbett, baritone; unidentified orchestra; Wilfred Pelletier, conductor
        Victrola: B 7959A-2A, C 7959B-1
      - Gounod, Charles, 1818-1893. Ave Maria (Vocal version); arr. -- Braga, Gaetano, 1829-1907. Serenata; arr., 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 17, Disc 714)
      - Debussy, Claude, 1862-1918. Sonatas, violin, piano -- Debussy, Claude, 1862-1918. Preludes, piano, book 1. Minstrels, 1929; 2 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 17, Disc 715-716)
        Performed by Alfred Cortot, piano; Jacques Thibaud, violin
        Victrola: B 8183A-2A, B 8183B-2; Cc16962 IIA[triangle] 3, CC16963 II[triangle] (matrix nos., disc 715); C8184A-2, A8184B-2; Cc16964 II[triangle], CC 16965 II[triangle] (matrix nos., disc 716)
      - Ravel, Maurice, 1875-1937. Rapsodie espagnole, 1934 March 17; 2 12" shellac 78 rpm sound discs (Box 17, Disc 717-718)
        Victor: B 8282A, C 8282B (matrix, disc 717); B 8283A, B 8283B (matrix, disc 718)
        Recorded March 17, 1934
      - Gounod, Charles, 1818-1893. Faust. Avant de quitter ces lieux -- Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Tannhäuser. O du mein holder Abendstern, 1934 April 20; 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 17, Disc 719)
        Title on label: Avant de quitter ces lieux (Even bravest heart) (Act 2) -- O du mein holder Abendstern (Evening star) (Act 3)
        Performed by Lawrence Tibbett, baritone (in French [side A] and German [side B]); unidentified orchestra
        Victor: 8452A-1, U 8452B
        Recorded April 20, 1934
      - Lyadov, Anatoly Konstantinovich, 1855-1914. Russkie narodnye pesni, orchestra. Selections, 1934 March 17; 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 17, Disc 720)
        Title on label: Eight Russian folk dances: No. 1-Religious chant -- No. 2-Christmas carol-Kolyada Maleda -- No. 3-Plaintive melody -- No. 4-Humorous song-The buzzing and biting of the gnat (Liadow)
        Victor: F 8491A-1, G 8491B-1
      - Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Tristan und Isolde. Liebestod, 1935 October 9; 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 17, Disc 721)
        Title on label: Tristan und Isolde-Isoldes liebestod (Isolde’s love-death) (Act 3)
        Performed by Kirsten Flagstad, soprano; unidentified orchestra; Hans Lange, conductor
        Victor: [upside down V] 8859A 1, [portion of upside down V] 8859B 1
        Recorded October 9, 1935
      - Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Don Juan, 1927?; 2 12" shellac 78 rpm sound discs (Box 17, Disc 722-723)
        Title on label: Don Juan (Tone-poem after Nicholas Lenau)
        Performed by Symphony Orchestra [unidentified]; Alfred Coates, conductor
        Victrola: E 9114A-1, D 9114B-2; CR 770-I[triangle], CR 771-II[triangle] (matrix nos., disc 722); G 9115A-2, A 9115B-2; CR 772-II[triangle], CR 773-II[triangle] (matrix nos., disc 723)
        Recorded in London, October 15, 1926
      - Respighi, Ottorino, 1879-1936. Fontane di Roma, 1927 January 4; 2 12" shellac 78 rpm sound discs (Box 17, Disc 724-725)